edukart.com 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy - EduKart

Earth Education Valley Private Limited (“EV”) are the owners of this website. We respect your right to privacy while being fully committed to fight spam. Please read the following statement to learn about our information gathering and dissemination practices.  
**Note:**  
Our Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time without notice. To make sure you are aware of any changes, please review this policy periodically.  
By visiting this website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access our website.  
By mere use of the website, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the Terms of Use.  
**Collection and Use of Personal Information**  
EV may, in the course of or for the purpose of facilitating the provision of services to users, collect various personal information such as email addresses, names, phone numbers, mobile numbers, date of birth, home address, educational and professional qualifications, data shared on social networking sites, as well as responses to survey forms, contests, quizzes and other marketing and promotional activities organised by EV (“Personal Information”) The Personal Information you submit to receive information and Services from EV will never be disclosed to any third party. Provided however, that EV may provide such Personal Information or part thereof, to the extent required to facilitate the performance of Services to users of EV’s Services, to its employees, affiliate entities, franchisees, sub-contractors, collaborating universities or educational institutions, third party email service providers providing marketing support to EV, consultants etc., (“EV Associates”) each of which shall be under a strict obligation to maintain the confidentiality of such Personal Information. Provided further, that the obligation to maintain confidentiality of Personal Information will not extend to any information that was publicly known and generally available in the public domain prior to the time of disclosure by you; or to information which becomes publicly known and generally available after disclosure by you through no action or inaction of ours; information which is already in our possession at the time of disclosure by you; is obtained by us from a third party without a breach of such third party’s obligations of confidentiality.  
We undertake not to provide any one other than EV Associates your contact details, including your e-mail ID, unless and until you enter it yourself. However, people / organizations whose e-mail IDs are obtained by us through this site may be included in our own mailing list for communications on our product / service innovations and relevant news. Recipients of such communications, however, will be free to unsubscribe from our mailing lists at any time simply when they send a message back stating “Unsubscribe”.  
We also undertake not to make any individual or organization other than an EV Associate, privy to the contents of any correspondence with us irrespective of whether the correspondence is made electronically through this site or by conventional means.  
Notwithstanding the above, with respect to all Users, EV and the EV Associates reserve the right to disclose any Personal Information, content, records, or electronic communication of any kind (including personal information transmitted through our site) in one or more of the following circumstance  
1\. To comply with any law, regulation, or government order;  
2\. To help prevent and detect identity theft, fraud and other potentially illegal acts;  
3\. If such disclosure is necessary to operate EV, or any of its business units, or EV Associates or for the purpose of providing joint or co-branded services with EV Associates;  
4\. In case we plan to merge with, or be acquired by another business entity, we may share or sell such information with such entity, or in case of re-organization, amalgamation, restructuring of business. Should such a transaction occur that other business entity (or the new combined entity) will be required to follow this or any equivalent privacy policy with respect to your personal information; .and  
5\. To protect the property and/or legitimate rights of EV or its associates, investors, customers, employees and suppliers.  
**Use of cookies** – A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer’s hard disk so that the website can remember who you are.  
A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the ‘lifetime’ of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.  
When you visit our website we send you a cookie. Cookies may be used in the following ways:  
1\. To help us recognise you as a unique visitor (just a number) when you return to our website and to allow us to tailor content or advertisements, including for the purpose of matching your preferred interests or to avoid showing you the same adverts repeatedly.  
2\. To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our site and to help us improve the structure of our website. We cannot identify you personally in this way.  
Two types of cookies may be used within this website: ‘session cookies’, which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site, and ‘persistent cookies’, which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie).  
**Disabling/Enabling Cookies** – You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our site if cookies are disabled.  
There are a number of ways to manage cookies. If you use different computers in different locations you will need to ensure that each browser is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences.  
Some modern browsers have a feature that will analyse website privacy policies and allow a user to control their privacy needs. These are known as ‘P3P’ features (Privacy Preferences Platform).  
You can easily delete any cookies that have been installed in the cookie folder of your browser. For example, if you are using Microsoft Windows Explorer:  
1\. Open Windows Explorer  
2\. Click on the Search button on the Tool bar  
3\. Type ‘cookie’ into the search box for Folders and Files  
4\. Select My Computer in the Look In box  
5\. Click Search Now  
6\. Double click on the folders that are found  
7\. Select any cookie file  
8\. Hit the Delete button on your keyboard  
If you are not using Microsoft Windows Explorer, then you should select cookies in the Help function for information on where to find your cookie folder.  
**IP Addresses**  
Your IP address maybe used to fix problems that may arise in our server or for statistical analysis which can help us to create a better experience for our users.  
**Payment Security**  
We do not collect any payment information on our site. Our payment gateway transactions are handled by multiple third party payment gateways, which have adherence to the highest levels of network and information security compliance. This ensures that your account information is well protected and completely secure. However, EV is not responsible for the privacy practices of the third party payment gateways and in the event of breach of any applicable law, unauthorised disclosure or misuse of payment information by such third party payment gateways, EV shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever.  
EV also uses cash on delivery services for collection of payments from the customers. However, EV is not responsible for the privacy practices of the companies that it uses to execute cash on delivery transactions and in the event of breach of any applicable law, unauthorised disclosure or misuse of payment information by companies, EV shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever.  
**Third-party Links/Websites**  
The EduKart.com website may contain links to other websites. EVis not responsible for the privacy practices or the content on the third party websites.  
**Deleting Accounts**  
Please email us at support@edukart.com and we will process your request to delete your account.  
**Reach Us -**  
In accordance with Information Technology Act 2000 and rules made there under, the name and contact details of the grievance officer of EV are provided below:  
Name: Mr. Karan Khurana  
Email: support@edukart.com  
Phone: 011 – 49879822
